<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>John DeTreville&#x27;s Blog</title>
    <link href="https://detreville.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://detreville.github.io" />
    <updated>2022-06-19T22:38:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>John DeTreville</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://detreville.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Fatherhood</title>
        <author>
            <name>John DeTreville</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://detreville.github.io/fatherhood.html"/>
        <id>https://detreville.github.io/fatherhood.html</id>
            <category term="Personal"/>

        <updated>2022-06-19T22:38:00-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/24626FBF-5309-4044-BA1F-AEA396C281A6_1_201_a.jpeg" alt="Thing 1 and Thing 2, by Dr. Seuss" />
                    Today is Father's Day in the US, so this blog post is about fatherhood. I started composing this blog post in my head as I slept in late this morning—without any small children jumping up and down on top of me like in the good&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/24626FBF-5309-4044-BA1F-AEA396C281A6_1_201_a.jpeg" alt="Thing 1 and Thing 2, by Dr. Seuss" />
                
  <p>
    Today is Father's Day in the US, so this blog post is about fatherhood. I started composing this blog post in my head as I slept in late this morning—without any small children jumping up and down on top of me like in the good old days—but writing it all down took a little more skill than I expected, because of course. At least it isn't midnight yet.
  </p>

  <p>
    My wife Laurie and I have two sons; one is 23 years old and one is 22½. Since they'd be horribly embarrassed to see their names here—each for his own excellent reasons—I'll just write "our first son" and "our second son," respectively.
  </p>

  <p>
    We adopted both our sons at their births, which is why their ages differ by only 7 months and 11 days. (Pro Tip to Self: Think "7-Eleven" to recall this, but don't ever mention such a silly shortcut to anyone.) It's incredibly difficult to raise two children so close in age, but you don't have to change diapers, then stop changing diapers for a while, then have to start all over again.
  </p>

  <p>
    This post is about our first son, since that was when my fatherhood began.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    I'm a lifelong techie. I'd long ago read Richard Dawkin's theory that parents love and protect their children because the parents and the children share genes, and because our genes control our behavior, and so and so on. If my son shares half my chromosomes, and he's suddenly in mortal danger, my genes might decide that saving him is worth sacrificing myself, assuming that doing so gives my son's copies of those very same crafty genes a better chance to live on. It's a very simple explanation of very complex behavior, so it made complete sense (to me).
  </p>

  <p>
    But what about adoption? I knew our adopted children and I would share <i>lots</i> of genes—like most humans, if I understand vertebrate zoology—but <i>not</i> as many as regular old biological parents do. Also, while biological parents get several months to prepare themselves for parenthood, pre-bonding with their imminent offspring, we didn't learn that yes, we'd soon have a son until just over a week before he was born. It was enough time to buy a car seat and cute baby clothes, but would I have enough time to pre-bond too? (My wife would know what to do, I was sure, but I was just the father, and a techie to boot. I had a Ph.D. in Computer Science, but I couldn't quite see how that helped.)
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a.jpeg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-md.jpeg 768w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/3CEE2715-65D8-4061-8E4C-F34FC467C16E_1_201_a-2xl.jpeg 1600w"  height="1425" width="1416" alt="Album cover, "Paul Simon With Bob Dylan: Summer of 1999"" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    It was the Summer of 1999 and the early days of dad-rock. We already had tickets for a big outdoor concert on Sunday night—Bob Dylan and Paul Simon!—and we knew his due date was Monday. I figured we'd see the concert, then drive straight to the local hospital where he'd be born. Great plan; too bad it didn't work.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2.jpeg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-md.jpeg 768w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/D0CDBBF1-8DBE-4E9C-922D-B95B5F4F5EA4_1_201_a-2-2xl.jpeg 1600w"  height="1116" width="1440" alt="The Sony VAIO PCG-C1 Picturebook, with built-in camera" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    It was late the <i>next</i> day when the call came in. I grabbed my nifty&nbsp;Sony VAIO PCG-C1 Picturebook laptop (what a name!) with its built-in camera. I figured we'd drive to the hospital, wait for our son to be born, snap some JPEGs, and mail them to our friends.
  </p>

  <p>
    And this time my plan worked!
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a.jpeg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-md.jpeg 768w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-lg.jpeg 1024w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-xl.jpeg 1360w ,https://detreville.github.io/media/posts/4/responsive/1715CBE8-1417-42C8-8BE4-C52FD1B26EBC_1_201_a-2xl.jpeg 1600w"  height="819" width="540" alt="The Selfish Gene, by Richard Dawkins" />
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    But what about the theory that parents love and protect the children because&nbsp;
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My new blog, and welcome to it!</title>
        <author>
            <name>John DeTreville</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://detreville.github.io/the-first-post-to-my-new-blog.html"/>
        <id>https://detreville.github.io/the-first-post-to-my-new-blog.html</id>
            <category term="Administrivia"/>

        <updated>2022-06-19T17:13:42-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is a first post to my new blog (and it's about time)! This blog is a simple static website. I'm hosting my blog on GitHub Pages. It's dead-simple and free. All pages are served straight from GitHub Pages, with no other server-side processing. I&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is a first post to my new blog (and it's about time)!</p>
<p>This blog is a simple static website. I'm hosting my blog on <a href="https://pages.github.com/" title="GitHub Pages | Websites for you and your projects, hosted directly from your GitHub repository. Just edit, push, and your changes are live." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Pages</a>. It's dead-simple and free. All pages are served straight from GitHub Pages, with no other server-side processing.</p>
<p>I started an old blog a few years ago using <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/" title="Jekyll • Simple, blog-aware, static sites | Transform your plain text into static websites and blogs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jekyll</a>, but I grew tired of wondering whether Jekyll would be maintained very far into the future, so I didn't write much. I've finally switched to <a href="https://getpublii.com/" title="Static Site CMS to build privacy-focused, fast and SEO-friendly website" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Publii</a> instead; it's a different static site generator and seems a little more modern. We'll see!</p>
<p>I intend to write about one new post a week. (I'm retired and have nothing else to do.) Let's seet how I do!</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
